

My name is Cesar Hernández, I'm assistant professor at Facultad de Economia and Chief Data Scientist at The Alan Turing Lab. I'm passionate about economics, data analysis, statistics and programming.

Scan QR code and visit Turing Finance, the best financial information platform:



# **SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE:**

- Advanced R
- Advanced Python
- Advanced Power BI
- Advanced Excel
- Advanced HTML
- Information Analysis
- Time Series Forecasting
- Cryptocurrencies
- Surveillance Capitalism

# **CONTACT:**

Phone: (55) 19694574 e-mail: cghv94@outlook.es Web: https://cghv94.github.io/ LinkedIn: https://n9.cl/ujduz

Turing Finance, financial information platform: https://turinglab.shinyapps.io/turingfinance/

Revista Estadística Practica

https://estadistica-practica.github.io/

## PROFESIONAL REFERENCES:

David Luna - alanturinglab@gmail.com
The Alan Turing Laboratory S.A.S. de C.V.
Arturo Mérida - merida@economia.unam.mx
Facultad de Economía. UNAM.

# CESAR GERARDO HERNÁNDEZ VARGAS

CHIEF ECONOMIST - CHIEF DATA SCIENTIST - ASSISTANT PROFESSOR

# **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

#### THE ALAN TURING LABORATORY S.A.S. DE C.V.

#### Chief Economist - Chief Data Scientist

august de 2021 - present

Mexico City, Mexico

Research and development of artificial intelligence platforms, financial information analysis and natural language processing.

# **FACULTAD DE ECONOMIA, UNAM**

#### **Assistant Professor Of Economics**

july 2018 - Present

Mexico City, Mexico

Statistics, Mathematics, Research and economic analysis, as well as statistical programming courses.

# PUED, UNAM

#### Research Assistant

march 2016 - january 2017

Mexico City, Mexico

Collaborated in the Energy chapter of the "Mexico Development Report: Development Perspectives to 2030". Management, manipulation and analysis of databases.

# **PUBLICATIONS:**

# REVISTA ESTADÍSTICA PRÁCTICA

2020 - Present

Direction and edition. Statistics Magazine of the Facultad de Economía. Dozens of articles that use statistics and R programming to explain economics, COVID19, gender-based violence, and sports

## **EDUCATION:**

# **FACULTAD DE ECONOMIA, UNAM**

2013 - 2018

Economics